A Guide to the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Welfare Interests - Youth, Series R FA327
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Young Women's Christian Association (YWCA)
  - Young Women's Christian Association - New York City - Contributions - November 15, 1929 Pledge for New York City Work, 1929-1930 (Box 42, Folder 467)
  - Young Women's Christian Association - New York City - Contributions - November 10, 1932 Pledge for New York City Work, 1932-1933 (Box 42, Folder 468)
  - Young Women's Christian Association - New York City - Contributions - November 13, 1930 Pledge for Budget, 1930-1931 (Box 42, Folder 469)
  - Young Women's Christian Association - New York City - Contributions - November 25, 1933 Pledge for Budget, 1933-1934 (Box 42, Folder 470)
  - Young Women's Christian Association - New York City - Contributions - November 10, 1931 Pledge for Deficit, 1931-1932 (Box 42, Folder 471)
  - Young Women's Christian Association - New York City - Contributions - November 7, 1945 Stock Gift, 1945-1946 (Box 42, Folder 472)
  - Young Women's Christian Association - New York City - Metropolitan Board - Mortgages, 1920-1927 (Box 42, Folder 473)
    List of mortgages outstanding on Young Women's Christian Association property in New York City. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Mrs. William F. Morgan, Raymond B. Fosdick, Willard S. Richardson, Arthur Woods, C. Belknap.
  - Young Women's Christian Association - New York City - Metropolitan Board - Mortgages - May 11, 1921 Loan to Association, 1921-1923 (Box 42, Folder 474)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. loan to assist in mortgage payments.
  - Young Women's Christian Association - New York City - Metropolitan Board - Mortgages - June 22, 1923 Pledge, 1923-1928 (Box 42, Folder 475)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. pledge to mortgage indebtedness on Metropolitan Branch.
  - Young Women's Christian Association - New York City - Metropolitan Board - Mortgages - 337-341 East 17th Street, 1924-1929 (Box 42, Folder 476)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. pledge to fund for temporary financing of removal of Gramercy Park Branch from former location to 17th Street.
  - Young Women's Christian Association - New York City - Metropolitan Board - Mortgages - Gramercy Park Property, 1920-1925 (Box 42, Folder 477)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. loan to Young Women's Christian Association enabling them to purchase Princeton Club property on Gramercy Park; extension of Empire Mortgage Company mortgage; information regarding marble mantelpiece in building.
  - Young Women's Christian Association - New York City - Joint Committee of New York, 1906 (Box 42, Folder 478)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. pledge to work of committee attempting reconciliation between two Young Women's Christian Association groups. Correspondents include Grace H. Dodge, Starr J. Murphy, Frederick T. Gates, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Young Women's Christian Association - New York City - West Side Branch, 1956-1957 (Box 42, Folder 479)
    Plans for opening a new residence on West Side, to replace Spelman Hall; new building named Spelman Residence Club. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
  - Young Women's Christian Association - New York City - West Side Branch - Opening, 1959 (Box 42, Folder 480)
    Attended by John D. Rockefeller 3rd, who made a short speech.
  - Young Women's Christian Association - New York City - Tatham House, 1926-1929 (Box 42, Folder 481)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. pledge and supplemental pledge for construction of annex to Tatham House. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Raymond B. Fosdick, Thomas M. Debevoise, Charles O. Heydt.
  - Young Women's Christian Association - New York City - United Appeal of Greater New York, 1947-1948 (Box 43, Folder 482)
    Joint campaign for funds for Manhattan, Bronx, Brooklyn, and Queens YMCAs; reports; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributions. Correspondents include Arthur W. Packard, Dana S. Creel, Mrs. Edward P. Townsend.
  - Young Women's Christian Association - New York City - United Appeal of Greater New York - Contributions, 1947-1952 (Box 43, Folder 483)
  - Young Women's Christian Association - New York City - Harlem, 1925 (Box 43, Folder 484)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contribution for Young Women's Christian Association Residence for Negro girls in Harlem, 1925; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Abby Aldrich Rockefeller aid to Young Women's Christian Association Employment Agency, 1931. Clippings. Correspondents include Willard S. Richardson, Arthur W. Packard, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Mrs. E. P. Townsend, Mrs. W. W. Rossiter.
  - Young Women's Christian Association - New York City - Harlem, 1926-1961 (Box 43, Folder 485)
  - Young Women's Christian Association - New York City - Harlem - Additional Land and Building, 1929-1931 (Box 43, Folder 486)
    Problems facing New York City YMCAs; purchase of West 138th Street property; transfer of property from John D. Rockefeller, Jr. pledge to fund for construction and furnishing of new building. Correspondents include Thomas B. Appleget, Charles O. Heydt, Raymond B. Fosdick, Mrs. W. Hays, Trevor Arnett.
  - Young Women's Christian Association - New York City - Harlem - June 19, 1930 Pledge, 1930-1934 (Box 43, Folder 487)
  - Young Women's Christian Association - New York City - Building and Program Fund Campaign, 1950-1953 (Box 43, Folder 488)
    Summary of gifts by Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial to Young Women's Christian Association; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. $520,000 contribution to campaign; declination of invitations. David and Margaret (Peggy) McGrath Rockefeller act as patrons of 80th birthday dinner. Campaign progress. Correspondents include Arthur Jones, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Mrs. W. C. White, David Rockefeller, Laurance S. Rockefeller.
  - Young Women's Christian Association - New York City - Building and Program Fund Campaign, 1950-1953 (Box 43, Folder 0488A)
  - Young Women's Christian Association - Providence, Rhode Island, 1901-1902 (Box 43, Folder 489)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. pledge to building fund on behalf of Abby Aldrich Rockefeller. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, Mrs. John Nightingale.
  - Young Women's Christian Association - Rock Hill, South Carolina, 1914-1929 (Box 43, Folder 490)
    Contributions by girls to Belgian Relief; school's request for fund for social and religious activities building; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. pledge. Letters introducing President Johnson. Correspondents include Willard S. Richardson, Starr J. Murphy, Thomas B. Appleget, D. B. Johnson.
  - Young Women's Christian Association - Washington, District of Columbia, 1910-1921 (Box 43, Folder 491)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. pledge toward cost of building terrace, Young Women's Christian Association cafeteria. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy, Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, Willard S. Richardson, E. F. Pierce.
  - Young Women's Christian Association - Washington, District of Columbia - 1925 Appeal, 1925-1927 (Box 43, Folder 492)
    Application for contribution to building fund; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. pledges.
  - Young Women's Christian Association - World Committee, 1936-1959 (Box 43, Folder 493)
    Abby Aldrich Rockefeller contributed to World Fund; material on World Emergency Fund. List of Rockefeller contributions to National Board and World Council, 1935-1944. Pamphlet on "Effects of World War II on Women"; Abby Aldrich Rockefeller contributions to Reconstruction Fund. Report on Young Women's Christian Association situation in Germany, 1945. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. 1951 contribution to expenses of Council meeting in Beirut. Correspondents include Mrs. J. Finley, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, Arthur W. Packard, Ruth F. Woodsmall.
  - Young Women's Christian Association - World Committee - 1932 Appeal (Box 43, Folder 494)
    Council plans for 1933 convention in China; asked John D. Rockefeller, Jr. advice regarding Chinese situation, whether he would help pay traveling expenses of some of the delegates.
  - Young Women's Christian Association - World Reconstruction Fund, 1946-1949 (Box 43, Folder 495)
    Work of Foreign division of National Board; Mrs. Speer's report on Conference; contributions; analysis of program needs by area, year, and type of service. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Abby Aldrich Rockefeller contributions. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arthur W. Packard.
  - Young Women's Christian Association - Miscellaneous Appeals, 1918-1961 (Box 44, Folder 496)
    Arthur Jones recommendations to Chicago Young Women's Christian Association; miscellaneous appeals to various members of the family declined for policy reasons. Some small contributions. Correspondents include Arthur Jones, Mrs. Robert Speer, Dana S. Creel, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson A. Rockefeller, Thomas B. Appleget.
  - Young Women's Christian Association - Miscellaneous Appeals, 1957-1961 (Box 44, Folder 0496A)
  - Young Women's Christian Association - Miscellaneous Appeals - Denver YMCA, 1925-1926 (Box 44, Folder 497)
  - Young Women's Christian Association - Statements of Contributions - Metropolitan and National, 1922-1924 (Box 46, Folder 534)
    Statement of Receipts for current work of Young Men's Christian Association and Young Women's Christian Association's to which Mr. Rockefeller contributes, 1917-1918. Four pages.
  - Young Women's Christian Association - Daytona Beach, Florida, 1926-1939 (Box 46, Folder 535)
    1) Agenda for Northeastern District Association Training Conference, October 25-27, no year. 2) Blueprint "Sketch of Proposed 'Y' Gym" upon Settlement of Peabody Estate, n.d.
  - Young Women's Christian Association - New York City - Contributions, 1937-1943 (Box 47, Folder 545)
    Young Women's Christian Association of the City of New York Balance Sheet as at December 31, 1941.
- Young Women's Hebrew Association
  - Young Women's Hebrew Association, 1912 (Box 44, Folder 498)
    John D. Rockefeller, Sr.'s pledge to building fund.